<surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" facs="#f000">
			<line>I was born in a Small town in Tenn the name Sewanee:</line>
			<line>So called. The University of the South. It was was 1893.</line>
			<line>My father was a white man. My mother was so called</line>
			<line>a negress. So I was looked on as a half white bastard</line>
			<line>and so called that by almost every one that knew me:</line>
			<line>.In. this town many of the better class of white people,</line>
			<line>often taken Negro boys-girl into their homes to train</line>
			<line>them to be effecient help. This is how my mother</line>
			<line>became a victim of this misfortune by producing me</line>
			<line>when she was seventeen. She descovered she was pregnet</line>
			<line>Her mistress sent her away. For me to be born.</line>
			<line>After this event. My mother was taken in by another family.</line>
			<line>by the name of Dr. Richerson. Who lived. next estate</line>
			<line>to my fathers people: I have never known. Jest why</line>
			<line>this kind couple should have so thoutful to mother.</line>
			<line>They treated her as if she was one of the family. When I was</line>
			<line>two years old my mother married. Then she brought</line>
			<line>me to live on the estate with her. and husband</line>
			<line>I was about three years old before I can remember</line>
			<line>things that went on about me: My step father</line>
			<line>was a fine man. He was so good to me although</line>
			<line>I became to know that he was not my father at</line>
			<line>four years old. Chrismas 1897. Usally my mother</line>
			<line>taken me up to mother Richeson to work every day</line>
			<line>their I would Play all over the house.. Mother Richeson</line>
			<line>was very fond of me. She done lots of hand work</line>
			<line>When I would do thinks wrong. She would. say</line>
			<line>I drop a stitch find it there I would crawl over the</line>
			<line>floor. hunting for the stitch. While both mothers</line>
			<line>would laugh; So this Xmas there was to be company</line>
			<line>for dinner. So my mother thought I would be in</line>
			<line>the way of the guest. So She explained this to me,</line>
			<line>Santa Claus had brought me some fire works</line>
			<line>and toys I was most happy. She ask me to stay in</line>
			<line>the servent quarters: until after dinner. And dont</line>
			<line>touch the fire works: She dressed me in a little</line>
			<line>plaid dress. And told me to stay in the house it was</line>
			<line>bitter cold out side snow on the Ground. The drum</line>
			<line>stove was red hot. When she left for work.</line>
		</surface>