<surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" facs="#f003">
			<line>I did'nt have any children to play with. I had my mother and</line>
			<line>father. They were like two pals. we didnt have any company.</line>
			<line>except. My fathers friends that worked on the construction</line>
			<line>When it rained. The men often came to the house to play</line>
			<line>checkers. Which my step father was a good player.</line>
			<line>no one had anything much to say to me: I was always</line>
			<line>busy trying to build something are make somthing.</line>
			<line>my mother when She was off the job she started me on my</line>
			<line>alphebet when I was four years old. I had to count</line>
			<line>every thing that came in the house. From my fathers</line>
			<line>pay enelope. To the matches in boxs. Some times I</line>
			<line>would complain. Then she would tell me that she wanted</line>
			<line>me to be the best edjacated man in the world. When I would</line>
			<line>go to mother Richeson house. I had to do the same thing: mother</line>
			<line>Richeson when I was four and a half. Bought me a slate and started me</line>
			<line>She called Father Gerry. To come and babtize me. The next</line>
			<line>day Father came: With him came Bishop Gailor of Tenn.</line>
			<line>and Father Clabourne. When they taken me in the parlor</line>
			<line>I became frighten and tryed to run out. My mother caught</line>
			<line>me and held on to me. They had on their corters and</line>
			<line>gouns which I had never seen them dressed like this.</line>
			<line>Mother Richinson and Bishop Gaitor kneelt by and told</line>
			<line>me. I was a child of God and I must be babtized and</line>
			<line>Bishop was my Godfarther- Mother Richeson was</line>
			<line>my Godmother. and father Gerry and father Eastern</line>
			<line>would be my consulman: When this was over I was</line>
			<line>most happy to know that I had so many friends</line>
			<line>I began to love every body: Hear I wish to explain</line>
			<line>somthing about this town. As why the white people</line>
			<line>were so democratic. Most of the people at this time</line>
			<line>that lived here. Were English decent. There many of them</line>
			<line>were nobility respect of England: The residental area was</line>
			<line>fenced in no poor white people lived in side of this area:</line>
			<line>No body lived there except the aristicrats and their servants.</line>
			<line>all work s like house maids Butlers coachmans were all.</line>
			<line>colored and most every one was call colored you</line>
			<line>rarely ever heard the word ever used negro are nigger.</line>
			<line>It seemed that every body was happy just to be there</line>
		</surface>