<surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" facs="#f004">
			<line>When I was five years old my little brother was born.</line>
			<line>In which. I became jelouis of imeditately. It seemed every</line>
			<line>thing changed. Every way. People came to our house to</line>
			<line>to see my little brother: Every one colored was so fond of.</line>
			<line>him. Until this happend: There were so few women</line>
			<line>ever come to see my mother: There were but few ever</line>
			<line>had anything. To say to me. They would just look at</line>
			<line>me as if I could not have been. My white family was</line>
			<line>named Wicks. Some of the women would say to</line>
			<line>the other he sure is a Wicks. He is just like them:</line>
			<line>by the time I was Six Year old: I had become to under</line>
			<line>stand that I just was nt like the rest of my family</line>
			<line>I know my mother had become to notice my feeling. Though</line>
			<line>she did not say anything to me concerning this: They gave</line>
			<line>me more priviledges. I was allowed to go out in the</line>
			<line>park and play withe the white children. when their</line>
			<line>nurses brought then in the Park to play. many</line>
			<line>times the mother s would come with their children. They</line>
			<line>were all so kind to me you see the town was so</line>
			<line>no houses had any numbers. every body knew</line>
			<line>every body Black ore white: The white people had</line>
			<line>every thing under such control. They knew every thing</line>
			<line>so that was why that it seemed that every one knew</line>
			<line>me and was so kind to me: So often they would</line>
			<line>bring ice crem cookies. I would be sirved with their</line>
			<line>children: This went on for about six months. Then my</line>
			<line>mother told me that school was opening out of the</line>
			<line>corporation and I should go. This was where most</line>
			<line>of the colored people and the poor class of white</line>
			<line>lived. So the first day she taken me to school so</line>
			<line>I would know the way. I met the teecher. and I was</line>
			<line>enrolled: For two weeks, I went to school. I did not</line>
			<line>like school. Because the children didnt like me</line>
			<line>I was the only real light complected one in</line>
			<line>the school. The rumer soon was out that I was a</line>
			<line>Bastard and that my white uncle was a knit witt</line>
			<line>whome was called Clabber: Soon all the children</line>
			<line>joked fun at me of this name: which vexed me very</line>
		</surface>