<surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" facs="#f005">
			<line>On Sundays my step father would be home with my</line>
			<line>mother. That was why I could go away for a while:</line>
			<line>I would come in and tell her how wonderful things</line>
			<line>were. Very soon my mother became so sick that I</line>
			<line>could not wait on her: Father had to get some.</line>
			<line>one a woman to care for. I had my little brother</line>
			<line>then to look after: Father built another room on</line>
			<line>to the one we had been living in where we cooked</line>
			<line>slept and bathed in: Father Gerry come Pastor of</line>
			<line>St Agustus came every morning. He and Dr Hall.</line>
			<line>Father would pray: And before he would he would</line>
			<line>leave. he would talk to me telling to stay close to</line>
			<line>her. many of the white family would drive up in</line>
			<line>carrages bringing somthing for her. They were</line>
			<line>so genorous in every way. So one morning</line>
			<line>Farther ask me would I like to go home with him.</line>
			<line>I went he only lived a block from us. This was</line>
			<line>the first time I had gone to any one s home. We</line>
			<line>went in. He had three children Elexandra. Annie</line>
			<line>Edward. his wife whom we called mother. She often</line>
			<line>taught neighborn children like a kindergarten:</line>
			<line>So almost every day except Sunday. I would go.</line>
			<line>with father home to play with the children at</line>
			<line>recess. Sometimes stayed all night because I was</line>
			<line>in the way. at home: and Mother Gerry was just</line>
			<line>about the sweetest lady I ever knew: She was so.</line>
			<line>kind. I did not attend Class althoug She explain</line>
			<line>any thing I ask her and treated me like other</line>
			<line>children. This al so made me very happey.</line>
			<line>Just here is the first time I had to learn something</line>
			<line>about religions: I hadnt ever seen may mother</line>
			<line>go to church nor my step farther. So one morning</line>
			<line>before Farther Gerry came Mother ask me not to go</line>
			<line>over to the Gerry home: That Elder Trouble</line>
			<line>was coming. And I might be need. So when</line>
			<line>He arrived with him was four women: They</line>
			<line>came. I took my little out side to play. They sang</line>
			<line>and prayed for many hours.</line>
		</surface>