<surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" facs="#f007">
			<line>All at once there was a scream. Which I knew it</line>
			<line>mothers voice. I rushed in the house. There my</line>
			<line>mother was sitting up in bed. Clapping hands saying</line>
			<line>Glory Hallalula. I been born again I rushed to her</line>
			<line>as she said my son I am now happy. I didnt know</line>
			<line>what it all ment. As I looked at all six people with tears</line>
			<line>streaming down their faces. Mother held out her</line>
			<line>hands saying bring my two sons to me. I turned</line>
			<line>around to get my brother who was crawling in the</line>
			<line>door. I carried him to the bed one of the sisters put him</line>
			<line>in the bed and I climbed in. Mother as feble as she was</line>
			<line>pulled us both against her breast and folded</line>
			<line>back on her pillar say God bless them I can</line>
			<line>now die happy. As she ran her feeble fingers through</line>
			<line>the curls of my hair saying over and over. He</line>
			<line>leadeth me through green pastures and lie me</line>
			<line>down by still waters I will not fear to enter</line>
			<line>the vally of death. I will not be alone. Soon she</line>
			<line>was in a coma: I was going over to Father Gerry.</line>
			<line>I was told that Mother had confessed religion.</line>
			<line>When met Father Gerry I told him of this.</line>
			<line>Father took me by hand and said lets go to her</line>
			<line>at once. When we arrived every one of the colored</line>
			<line>people had gone. No one was there except Mother and her</line>
			<line>nurse. Father Gerry walked to her bedside. With</line>
			<line>his left hand he stroke her brow softly. The word s</line>
			<line>he spoke I cant remember. then he knelt by the bed</line>
			<line>with me and the lady nurse. There he prayed and talked</line>
			<line>with her. Mother spoke then, asking him what should</line>
			<line>be done with Ely. I know I am going die. Eddie he has a father</line>
			<line>to look after him. Ely as he is you know hasnt</line>
			<line>any one. I now can die happy when I know that he will</line>
			<line>be cared for. Farther then spoke saying Lena you know</line>
			<line>that Bishop Gaylor is Elys Godfather and I am his</line>
			<line>conselor. and Farther Eastern. He will be taken care of.</line>
			<line>Who do you think he could live with Mother told</line>
			<line>him to send for Matty Davis. Whom she had</line>
			<line>lived with when she was a girl. Father waited</line>
			<line>untill I went for her and came back.</line>
		</surface>