<surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" facs="#f008">
			<line>There was agreed. That Matty Davis would raise me.</line>
			<line>My mother was very happy. Father Gerray told Mother</line>
			<line>Matty that she would have help if she needed it.</line>
			<line>This was the begining of a new life for me: I left with</line>
			<line>her. That was the last time I saw my mother alive.</line>
			<line>She died the next day. My brother and his father moved</line>
			<line>out of the corporation. To where most of the colored people</line>
			<line>lived: soon he married again. My foster mother cooked</line>
			<line>for Dr. Barton. They let her keep me on the estate. They</line>
			<line>were very kind to me. I was then allowed to go almost</line>
			<line>anywhere I wanted to go. I would go to Father Gerrays</line>
			<line>house every day to play with the children. Mother Mat</line>
			<line>had three children one girl two boys. Her childre were</line>
			<line>grown: She owned a house where they lived. Neither</line>
			<line>of them were married. I soon became to love her.</line>
			<line>and daughters as if they were my own. When I was</line>
			<line>eight years old. Mama Matty decided. I should go</line>
			<line>to school. So we stop staying at night in the corporation</line>
			<line>she would go home: School did not open as was expected.</line>
			<line>So I would go to and frow. With her to work and</line>
			<line>to play with the white children. I often would go to</line>
			<line>building where my step father worked. To see him</line>
			<line>I loved him. He loved me to I knew. He was so kind</line>
			<line>everybody that knew him loved him white or black. He</line>
			<line>was so strong I just loved to be close to him. He was</line>
			<line>said to be the strongest man in the county. It was</line>
			<line>often he would display his strenth by lifting. To</line>
			<line>amuse the students who liked to watch him. His job</line>
			<line>mostly was to wind the derick for the stone setters.</line>
			<line>Just as I was turning nine. This was where things</line>
			<line>began to change for me and happiness faded:</line>
			<line>All this time my frienships had broadend. To where</line>
			<line>almost every notable in town knew me many of</line>
			<line>them would stop on the street and would talk to me.</line>
			<line>I was taught by Mother to be curtious to every one</line>
			<line>People liked me for this often told me that. I hadnt</line>
			<line>ever thought any thing about race destinction.</line>
			<line>I knew very little about colored children. The word Negro</line>
			<line>was rarely ever used, or I just didnt pay any attention</line>
		</surface>