<surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" facs="#f009">
			<line>I said no I didnt have a drink the clerk wouldn’t make</line>
			<line>me a drink. He called me a niggir and said he did</line>
			<line>not make drinks for niggirs: Mother stop looking</line>
			<line>at me and looked toward the fire. I stood there for</line>
			<line>a moment. Then I ask her Mother what is a nigger.</line>
			<line>She did not answer. She walked tothe hall and</line>
			<line>called the two boys to come to the libiary they came</line>
			<line>she said I have some cookies and will make some</line>
			<line>hot cholate. You dont have to go to the drug store.</line>
			<line>No one said anything. She went to the kitchen. I</line>
			<line>followed her. While she was heating the milk.</line>
			<line>I could see that she was a bit purturbed. Then I ask</line>
			<line>her would she please tell me what is a nigger.</line>
			<line>Why should I be called a nigger. It must be very</line>
			<line>bad to be a nigger. She stood with her back to</line>
			<line>me fully a minute. Before she spoke. She turned</line>
			<line>and faced me. She said Ely I think this is a job</line>
			<line>for Father: you go to him. He can explain this</line>
			<line>better than I can. He is over at St. Agustus. For three years</line>
			<line>I had been coming to her for understanding. This was</line>
			<line>the first time she refused to explain to me. I did not</line>
			<line>wait for choclate. I went over to St. Agustus Father</line>
			<line>Gerry was in his study. He was writing.He looked</line>
			<line>up and said Ely my boy what brings you here. I said</line>
			<line>Father there is something I want to ask you if you</line>
			<line>have time. He said Have a seat there. Ill talk to you in a</line>
			<line>minute: I waited soon he said I am preparing this for class</line>
			<line>and lecture this afternoon. Now what is it you</line>
			<line>want to know: Ely. I stood up. Then I said Father</line>
			<line>I want to know what is a nigger. I was called that</line>
			<line>by the clerk over at the drugstore. He would not take my</line>
			<line>money. Mother Gerry said I should come to you for</line>
			<line>explanation. He started to say something and stopted,</line>
			<line>just for a moment. Then he said Ely. I am very busy. I have</line>
			<line>this lecture to do so I will send you to Father Eastern</line>
			<line>tell him. I sent you and he will explain to you</line>
			<line>what you need to know. If you dont find him</line>
			<line>at home come back to morrow and I will</line>
			<line>talk to you. I thanked him and left.</line>
		</surface>