<surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" facs="#f001">
			<line>She came back ever hour to see how I was: The stove.</line>
			<line>was red from heat: So holding a roman candle in my hand</line>
			<line>playing with it I let it touch the stove. And it lighted</line>
			<line>and started to Sparkle. I tried to put it out it set my</line>
			<line>dress afire. I ran to the door and threw the candle out I was</line>
			<line>on fire. not knowing what to. I leapt in the bed and covered it.</line>
			<line>This put the fire out: Later I got up and changed .dresses and hid</line>
			<line>my burned dress in my box where I kept my clothes: Soon my</line>
			<line>mother came with my dinner. like most all the cooks down</line>
			<line>South feed their children from their jobs this is called toten.</line>
			<line>She had some toys and lot of nickels that Mother Richerson and</line>
			<line>the guest had sent me. while she was placing my dinner on</line>
			<line>my littel table she smelled the burnt cloth. . Then she ask</line>
			<line>me what happen. She wanted to know if I had shot any of</line>
			<line>my fire works: I told her no. soon she found I had lied:</line>
			<line>This was the first time I had ever remembered of eve being</line>
			<line>whipt: by her: So when she stopt whipping me I ran</line>
			<line>out in the snow screaming so loud that my mother had to</line>
			<line>try. run me down to get me back in the house. before she could</line>
			<line>reach me I had crawled through the bars of the big gate to the</line>
			<line>adjoyning estate: That belong to my father people. There I</line>
			<line>stood screaming. My mother stood coaxing me to come</line>
			<line>back to her: She didn't wish to come through gate:</line>
			<line>Some one spoke from the back of me. Asking my mother</line>
			<line>what was she whipping me for. Mother replied he lied</line>
			<line>to me and I spanked him and he ran away from me</line>
			<line>over there. So this white lady taken me by my hand</line>
			<line>house and come back to the gate she had something</line>
			<line>for me at the house. So mother taken me in and</line>
			<line>told me to stay untill she come back. She went out:</line>
			<line>Soon she was back with lots oranges and candy and toys</line>
			<line>She told me these were sent to you. I ask her who was the</line>
			<line>lady. She looked at me for a moment. And said you might</line>
			<line>as well know now. That was your grandmother</line>
			<line>of your white family. She said for you to be a good</line>
			<line>boy and dont tell storys to any one: This made me</line>
			<line>very happy to think some else loved me, to. No farther</line>
			<line>did I think of it. Later my step farther came he helpt</line>
			<line>me shoot my fire works. I was so fond of him.</line>
		</surface>