<surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" facs="#f004">
			<line>much: My teacher was very kind to untill I started</line>
			<line>to fight the kids when the the would tease me: I was</line>
			<line>graded: placed in the second Reader: Just as I was</line>
			<line>begenning to be come adjusted my mother taken</line>
			<line>sick. She wanted me to stay with her. She had been</line>
			<line>ailing every sice my brother was born. She never</line>
			<line>went back to work. So I was glad not to go to school.</line>
			<line>My mother was aflected with consumption: she know</line>
			<line>She would never be well. This four month before</line>
			<line>She got to weak she kept me with her almost every</line>
			<line>minute: She would take my brother and and go up on</line>
			<line>the main streets when the military student would</line>
			<line>march. by. I thought that was the greatest somthing</line>
			<line>that could be: To be a cadet. She talked so much about</line>
			<line>this training. Sundy morning the cadets would march.</line>
			<line>by music. by their band. like the West Point.</line>
			<line>Cadets. So on Sundy mornings I would go up on</line>
			<line>the street where they marched by: I was just two</line>
			<line>blocks from St Agustus Chapel. Which they had to</line>
			<line>march from where I would meet them. So I would</line>
			<line>try to keep up with them untill they got to the chapel.</line>
			<line>formation. Passing reveiw and salute their superiors.</line>
			<line>I would stand some where and solute to. Then march.</line>
			<line>in the chapel. Every body always waited for the arival</line>
			<line>of the cadets before going in the chapel. When they</line>
			<line>marched in. I wouldnt go in the I would to the back</line>
			<line>of the chapel to watch the orogan pumper pump the</line>
			<line>pipe organ. I would wath him for a while. Then</line>
			<line>I would go to my mother. After a few Sundays I</line>
			<line>was spoken to by many white people; All white people</line>
			<line>down South seems to love colored children. So one</line>
			<line>morning their was a package left on our door step</line>
			<line>I brought it in and gave it to my mother She open it</line>
			<line>their was a little coat and cap somthing like the</line>
			<line>cadets: So Sundy mornings I was always waiting</line>
			<line>for cadets to pass. Seem every body would laugh.</line>
			<line>when I pass by they would salute me when I salute</line>
			<line>them. I do beleaive that was the happiest days of all</line>
			<line>my life:</line>
		</surface>