<surface xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" facs="#f008">
			<line>I had the dream that some day I would be like the</line>
			<line>students. I would be a cadet. All the white kids talked of</line>
			<line>this we drilled and played to gather happily I didnt</line>
			<line>only go to Father Gerrys house. I would go to any</line>
			<line>ones house that had children. Have lunch. All these</line>
			<line>mothers were kind to me. One morning I went to</line>
			<line>Mother Gerrys to play. It was cold outside. There</line>
			<line>wasn’t any children except her own around. Mother</line>
			<line>said to us: The leaves has blown over the yard.</line>
			<line>If you boys will rake them up. I will give fifteen</line>
			<line>cents each. The job was soon done. When she paid us</line>
			<line>out to the drug store we went. To buy an egg flip which was</line>
			<line>a drink like a malted milk. Alexander, Edward and I.</line>
			<line>We went to the dispencer. And ordered three drinks.</line>
			<line>I had been here before many times with these children.</line>
			<line>And got drinks even men and women had given</line>
			<line>me drinks because I had no money. Dr. Conger the</line>
			<line>propiator never said anything. This day there was</line>
			<line>a new disspencer that I hadnt seen before. So he made</line>
			<line>two drinks. Handed one to Alexander another one to</line>
			<line>Edward. Didnt make any for me. I ask where was</line>
			<line>my drink. He said You don’t get any: Alexander</line>
			<line>spoke up why don’t Ely get a drink he has money to pay</line>
			<line>for it. The dispencer said I don’t make drinks for no</line>
			<line>nigger. He is a nigger. Alexander said he is one of us.</line>
			<line>The fellow said I wouldnt make a drink for a nigger</line>
			<line>if I never worked. The boys both tossed their glasses</line>
			<line>over the counter and out of the store we went back</line>
			<line>home. This was the first time I ever felt hurt except</line>
			<line>when my mother died: We were just a block from</line>
			<line>the Gerry home. We didnt talk at all on the way</line>
			<line>home. Alexander was two years older than I. and</line>
			<line>was older than Edward. I am not sure that Alexander</line>
			<line>did not have more understanding about this than</line>
			<line>we did. When we entered the house Alexander</line>
			<line>and Sumner went strait to their room. I walked to</line>
			<line>the libary where Mother Gerry and Annie was</line>
			<line>the libary where Mother Gerry and Annie was</line>
			<line>at me and said did you boys have a nice drink.</line>
		</surface>